[ Music ]
[ 音乐 ]
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
&gt;&gt; Hi, everybody.
&gt;&gt; 大家好
It's great to see you all here
非常高兴见到今天
today.
到场的各位
I'm Dave, and the next 40
我是 Dave 之后的 40 分钟
minutes are about understanding
是关于理解
and honoring what makes our
和致敬 驱动我们的
programs actually work.
程序运行的东西
There will be practical advice,
我们将会聊到一些实用的建议
but this is not a talk about
但这并不是一个关于
tips and techniques or any
技巧 技术
specific algorithms even, though
或者任何具体算法的演讲
we will look at a few.
尽管我们仍会有所涉及
It's about revealing something
这个演讲主要的内容是
fundamental, the potential of
揭示一些根本的东西 它的潜力
which is already present in your
已经在你的代码中有所体现
I hope that for at least a few
我希望至少对于你们之中的一些人
of you it marks the beginning of
这标志着与编程实践
a new relationship to the
建立新关系的开始
Speaking personally, when I
就个人而言
discovered this approach, it
当我发现这种方法时
changed the course of my life
我的生活和事业的航向
and my career.
就由此改变
It's the reason I care so much
这就是为什么
about software libraries, but
我如此关心软件库
it's also the source of the
但它也是
liability, maintainability, and
我所编写过的具体代码的
performance in every piece of
每一部分之中的可靠性
concrete code I've written
可维护性以及性能表现的来源
But before we get into that, let
但在我们开始之前
me introduce you to a friend of
请允许我向你们介绍
mine.
我的一个朋友
This is Crusty.
他就是 Crusty
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
Crusty is old school.
Crusty 是一个传统派
He doesn't trust debuggers or or
他不相信调试工具
mess around with integrated
也不爱使用集成开发环境
No, he favors an 80 x 24
没错 他喜欢那种 80 × 24
terminal window in plain text,
的纯文本终端窗口
thank you very much.
非常感谢
Now, Crusty takes a dim view of
现在 Crusty 对最新的编程潮流
the latest programming fads, so
持悲观态度
it can sometimes be an effort to
所以想把他拖到 21 世纪
drag him into the 21st century.
有时会比较费力
He just thinks different.
他总是有不同的想法
But if you listen carefully, you
但是如果你仔细听
can learn a thing or two.
你肯定会学到点东西
Now, sometimes his cryptic
有时他会有一些
pronouncements like "programming
神奇的表达方式
reveals the real; border on the
比如“编程揭示本真”  甚至可以说
mystical."
有点玄幻了
And to understand him, I found
为了理解他
it helpful to actually write
我发现一种方法很有帮助
some code.
那就是写代码
So, lately, I've been working on
所以最近我在编写
a little program called Shapes.
一个叫做《Shapes》的小程序
I'm hoping to make it into a
我希望将它创造成
full-featured vector drawing
一个全能矢量绘图程序
program, but so far it lets you
但目前为止 它只能让你
arrange shapes on an infinite
在无限画布上排列形状
Now, I want to tell you the
现在 我想与你们讲一个
story of the delete selection
关于删除选择指令的故事
command because I learned so
因为我从实现这一功能的过程中
feature.
学习到了很多
I think we've probably all gone
我想我们可能都
through part of this progression
经历过这个过程的一部分
as programmers as we learn how
作为程序员 我们要学会
to remove things from an array.
如何从数组中删除东西
Everybody starts out doing
每一个人都会从
something like this.
做这种事情开始
That's the delete selection
刚刚这个就是删除选择指令
We loop from 0 to count, and
我们从 0 开始循环计数
when we find something to
当我们发现要删除的东西
delete, we [inaudible] remove
我们就调用 remove(at: )方法
that, and then we continue with
然后我们就可以继续循环
our loop until, ouch, we walk
直到 哦 溢出了
The array got shorter, but we
数组会变短
picked the number of iterations
但是当循环开始时
when the loop started.
我们选择了固定的迭代次数
Fortunately, you can't miss this
幸运的是 如果你使用 Swift
bug if you Swift and test your
并测试你的代码 你不可能遗漏这个 Bug
code because it'll trap.
因为程序会产生内中断
But if you had to learn this
但如果你像我一样
lesson as a C-programmer, like I
是 C 语言出身的程序员
did, you might not be so lucky.
面对这种问题 你可能没那么幸运
Okay.
好的
So, we can fix it by replacing
我们可以通过将 for 循环替换为
the for loop with a somewhat
更难看的 while 循环
uglier while loop, which lets us
来修复它
examine the count at each
这可以使我们在每一次迭代中
iteration.
检查计数
But there's a subtle bug in this
但这里也有一个细微的 Bug
If two consecutive elements are
如果两个连续的元素被选中
selected, it'll remove the first
它将会删除第一个
one and then immediately hop
并且立即
over the next one.
跳过下一个
Now, this bug is a little more
这个 Bug 更加的阴险
insidious because it hides from
因为它隐藏了起来
you unless your tests happen to
除非你的测试碰巧
exercise it.
试运行了它
But if we're lucky enough to
但是如果我们足够幸运注意到了它
notice it, we press ahead and we
我们便可以继续
fix the implementation again by
用一个 else 代码块
guarding the increment in an
来保护自增语句 再次修复
else block.
这个实现
So, are we done now?
那么 我们完成了吗
Are we sure this one is correct?
我们有把握确定 这次是正确的吗
I think I can prove to myself
我认为我可以自证
that it works.
它能够运行
Anyway, having gone through this
不管怎样 经过这次的严峻的考验
ordeal, what do we do?
我们收获了什么
Well, of course, we lock this
当然 我们将这个
nine-line pattern into our
九行的代码套路 牢记在脑中
brains so we can trot it out
这样我们就可以在想要
whenever we have to delete
删除什么的时候 把它调出来
Now, I'm sure many of you have
现在 我确定你们中的许多人
been holding yourselves back
正控制着自己
from screaming at me because
不向我大声喊叫
that there's a much more elegant
因为有一个
way to do it.
更加优雅的方式可以用
I still remember the day I
我仍然记得 自己发现了
discovered this trick for myself
这个技巧的那一天
because once you find it, you
因为一旦你发现了它 你就不用
never do this nine-line dance
再用那九行套路代码了
The iteration limit and the
迭代限制以及
index of the next item to
下一个要检查的项的索引
examine kept shifting under our
像传送带一样不断滚动
feet because remove(at: i)
因为 remove(at: i)
changes parts of the array after
改变了数组中 i 之后的部分
But if you go backwards, you
但是如果你从后往前检查
only iterate over the parts of
你只会迭代数组中
the array that you haven't
你还没有改变的部分
Slick, right?
干得漂亮 对吗
And this is the pattern I've
这就是我一直
used ever since because it's
使用的模式
clean, and it never fails, until
因为它简洁并且从不失败
a few months ago.
直到几个月前
One morning, I had just finished
一天早晨 我刚吃完
my avocado toast, and I was idly
我的牛油果吐司
fooling with my app when I tried
并漫不经心地摆弄我的 App
deleting about half the shapes
当我尝试从一个非常复杂的画布中
from a really complicated
删除差不多一半的图形时
My iPad, it froze up for like
我的 iPad 卡死了
three seconds.
将近 3 秒钟
So, I took a sip of my half caf
所以 我喝了一口
triple shot latte in its bamboo
装在竹质随行保温杯里的
thermal commuter cup, and I
三倍浓度半因拿铁咖啡压压惊
considered my options.
开始考虑我的对策
This was disturbing.
这令人十分不安
I mean, it's a pretty
我的意思是 这是一个
straightforward operation, and
非常简单的操作
my code was so clean, how could
我的代码如此简洁
it be wrong?
怎么可能出错呢
Profiling showed me that the hot
性能分析结果告诉我
spot was right here, but beyond
红点就在这 但是除了这个
that, I was stumped.
我一点头绪都没有
So, just about then, Crusty
然后 就在这时
walked up behind me carrying a
Crusty 在我身后经过
can of off-brand coffee grounds
拿着一罐从当地超市买的
from the local supermarket for
准备作为日常饮品的
his daily brew.
杂牌咖啡
"Stuck?" he said.
“卡住了？” 他说
"Yeah," I sighed, and I
“是的” 我叹了口气
explained the situation.
并向他解释情况
"Well, did you even look at the
“那么 你有为此
documentation for that?"
看过文档吗？”
Well, I hadn't, so I popped up
显然我没有 所以我呼出了
the Quick Help for Remove At,
remove(at: ) 的 “Quick Help（快速帮助）”
and Crusty leaned in.
Crusty 靠近了一点
"There's your problem, right
“你的问题就在这”
there," he said, leaving a
他说 并在我华丽的
smudge on my gorgeous retina
视网膜显示屏上留下了一个指纹
Now, I carefully wiped off the
我用一块手工制作的
fingerprint with a handcrafted
意大利超细纤维布
Italian microfiber cloth, and
小心地擦掉了指纹
Crusty said, "What's that tell
这时 Crusty 说 “小子
you, son?"
它告诉你了什么”
"Well," I said, "it means that
“唔” 我说 “它说
removing an element takes a
移除一个元素
number of steps proportional to
需要使用大量的步骤
the length of the array."
而且与数组的长度成正比”
And it kind of makes sense,
这的确有些道理
since the array has to slide all
因为数组需要将
of the following elements into
之后所有的元素
their new positions.
放入它们的新位置
"So, what's that mean about your
“那么 这对你的删除选择指令
Delete Selection command?"
又有什么意义呢” 他问道
"Uh," I said.
“呃” 我说
That's when he pulled out a pack
就在这时他拿出
of mentholated lozenges and
一包薄荷糖
lined them up on my desk.
然后排成线放在我的桌子上
"Try it yourself."
“你自己试一试”
So, I went through the process
所以我走完一遍流程
as I tried to answer his
试图回答他的问题
"Well, since Delete Selection
“嗯 既然删除选择指令
has to do order n steps, once
需要进行 O(n) 个步骤
for each selected element, and
每一步都对应每一个已选的元素
you can select up to n elements,
而且你可以选择最多 n 个元素
the total number of steps is
那么总步数将与
proportional to n squared."
n 的二次方成正比”
Crusty added, "That's quadratic,
Crusty 继续说 “那可是二次方
son, whether you do it the ugly
小子 无论你用丑陋的方式正着走
forward way or the fancy pants
还是穿着花哨的
backward way."
裤子倒着来”
I realized then that for my
我那时才意识到
little 10 to 20-element test
对于我的 10 到 20 个元素的
cases, we'd only been talking
小型测试案例 我们只需使用
about a few hundred steps, and
几百个步骤
since the steps are pretty fast,
由于每一步都运行迅速
it seemed great.
一切看起来棒极了
But the problem is that it
但是问题是
doesn't scale well.
它的延展性不足
Fifty squared is 2,500 and 100
50 的二次方是 2500
squared is 10,000.
100 的二次方更能达到 10000
So, if you do all your testing
如果你所做的所有测试
in this little region down here,
都在这个狭小范围之内
you'll probably never see it,
那你可能永远发现不了问题
but scalability matters because
但是延展性很重要
people are using their phones
因为人们正在使用他们的手机和 iPad
and iPads to manage more and
处理越来越多的数据
more data, and we keep shipping
我们也一直提供带有
devices with more memory to help
更多存储空间的设备
them do it.
帮助他们这么做
You care about this because
你们要关心这一点
scalability is predictability
因为对你们的用户而言
for your users.
延展性意味着可预测性
So, now, I understood the
所以 我理解了问题所在
problem, but I still wasn't sure
但是我仍然不能确定
what to do about it.
我应该怎么解决它
"Now what?"
“现在我该怎么办？”
I asked Crusty.
我问 Crusty
"You know, kid," he said,
“你知道吗 小伙子” 他一边说
popping a lozenge, "there is an
一边把一粒薄荷糖放到嘴里
algorithm for that."
“有一个解决这个问题的算法”
I told him, "Listen, Crusty, I'm
我和他说 “听着 Crusty
an app developer.
我是一个 App 开发者
You say you don't do object
你说过你不做面向对象的东西
Well, I don't 'do' algorithms."
同样 我也不做算法
You pay attention to your data
你关注在算法类中的
structures in algorithms class
数据结构
because you know when it's time
因为你知道
to get a job, your interviewer
找工作的时候
is going to ask you about them.
你的面试官会考你
But in the real programming
但在真正的编程世界
world, what separates the elite
区分大神和菜鸟的关键
from the newbies is the ability
是将控制器 委托
to wire together controllers,
以及响应程序
delegates, and responders to
连接在一起
build a working system.
构建一个工作系统的能力”
"Bonkey," he said; I don't know
“豆包” 他说
why he calls me that, "What do
我不知道为什么他这么称呼我
computers do?"
“计算机是做什么的”
"They compute."
“它们计算”
"Now, where's the computation in
“那么 你的代码中的计算
all that?"
在哪里呢”
"Well," I replied, "I guess I
“好吧” 我回答
don't see anything that looks
“我想在我的代码里
like an algorithm in my code."
我看不见什么东西像个算法”
But Crusty wasn't having it.
但是 Crusty 不这么认为
"Oh, your app is full of them,"
“哦 你的 App 里面可全都是算法”
he said, dropping an old dead
他说 接着将一本破旧的字典
tree dictionary on my desk,
扔在我的桌子上
"Look it up."
“翻翻看”
After I gathered my composure, I
在我镇定下来后
carefully slid the book to one
我小心地将书移到一边
side and typed Define Algorithm
在聚焦搜索栏中输入
into Spotlight, which Crusty
“define: Algorithm (定义：算法)”
thought was a neat trick.
Crusty 认为这是个巧妙的技巧
Hmm.
嗯
A process or set of rules to be
在计算或其他解决问题的
followed in calculations or
运算中
other problem solving
要遵循的过程或规则集
Well, come to think of it, that
好吧 细想一下
did sound like most code, but I
这听起来像大多数的代码
still wasn't sure.
但是我仍不能确定
"You ever do a long division?"
“你有做过长除法吗”
asked Crusty.
Crusty 问道
"That's an algorithm."
“那就是一个算法”
I started to type into Spotlight
我又开始将它打到聚焦搜索中
again, but he snapped, "On
但是他突然说
paper."
“在纸上算”
And not wanting to embarrass
不想让自己难堪
myself, I turned the subject
我把话题转回到
back to my code.
我的代码上
"Hmm."
“嗯”
I asked, "So, what is this magic
我问 “所以 这个可以解决
algorithm that will cure my
我的代码性能问题的
performance problem?"
神奇的算法是什么呢”
"Well, if you'll just let me at
“那么 如果你愿意
your TTY there for a minute," he
让我用一下你的打字机”
said, "How do you work this
他说 “这个东西怎么用
thing?
哦 这是一个触控板
I'll try not to touch that.
我会尽量不碰它
So, first, you do away with this
所以首先 你要删掉这些
foolishness.
愚蠢的代码
Now, shapes.removeallwhere the
然后 shapes.removeAll
shape is selected.
(where: )
Hmm.
嗯
Try that on for size."
试试合不合身”
Now, Crusty headed off to wash
然后 Crusty 离开了
out the pitcher of his coffee
去洗他的咖啡机的拉花缸
maker, leaving me to figure out
留下我去琢磨
what had just happened in my
我的代码里到底
code.
发生了什么
First, I checked, and I found
首先 我检查过并且发现
that the performance problem was
性能问题确实解决了
Nice.
太棒了
And I didn't want another earful
我不想再听一遍
from Crusty about looking at the
Crusty 唠叨说看文档
documentation, so I popped up
所以我弹出 removeAll(where: ) 的
Quick Help for removeAll(where:
“Quick Help”
and I saw that its complexity
然后我发现它的复杂度
scales proportionally to the
也与集合的长度
length of the collection just
成正地变化
like removeAt.
就像 removeAt 一样
But since I didn't have to put
但是由于我不必
it in a loop, that became the
把它放入循环中
complexity of my whole
那么它就变成了我整个
operation.
运算的复杂度
Now, I want to give you some
现在 我想让你们
intuition for the kind of
直观地理解
difference this makes.
这能带来什么不同
What are n means that the time
O(n) 表示算法运行的时间
the algorithm runs scales
与问题的大小
linearly with the problem size.
成线性关系
The graph is a straight line.
这个图是一条直线
Now, the orange line is the
然后 这个橙色线是
shape of order n squared.
n 的二次方的形状
As you can see, a linear
正如你所见
algorithm may do worse on a
线性算法也许在小型问题中
small problem, but it's
表现稍差
eventually faster than a
但他最终比
quadratic algorithm.
二次方算法运行更快
The cool thing is though, it
很棒的是
doesn't matter how expensive you
不管你用线性算法
make the steps of the linear
的成本有多高
algorithm, if you keep looking
如果你继续放更大的问题尺寸
at larger problem sizes, you'll
你总是会找到
always find one where the linear
一个线性算法会赢
algorithm wins and continues to
并且在后面
win forever.
一直赢的点
So, we're talking about
所以 我们正在讨论的是
scalability, not absolute
延展性 而不是绝对的性能
Well, my scalability problem was
好了 我的延展性问题终于解决了
fixed, but I really wanted to
但我真的很想看看
see how the standard library had
标准程序库如何改进
improved on my backward deletion
我倒着来的删除方法
Crusty reminded me that Swift is
Crusty 提醒我说
open source, so I could pull it
Swift 是开放源码 所以我可以把它
up on what he calls "the hipster
放在他口中的“嬉皮士网”上
But the rest of us know as
也就是我们其他人所知的 GitHub
Now, the first thing I noticed
现在 我注意到的第一件事
was the dot comment, which was
便是点注释
the source of all that Quick
它是所有 “Quick Help” 的来源
Help, describing both what the
描述了算法的功能以及复杂度
Next, it turns out that
接下来 结果是
removeAll(where) isn't just some
removeAll(where) 不是什么
method on a reg; it's a generic
常规的方法
algorithm, which means that it
它是一个通用的算法
works on a wide variety of
这意味着
different collections.
它可以在各种不同的集合上运行
It depends on a couple of
这取决于很多因素
things, the ability to rearrange
重新排列元素的能力
elements, which comes from
它来自于
mutable collection, and the
MutableCollection
ability to change the length and
改变长度和结构的能力
structure, which comes from
它来自于
range-replaceable collection.
RangeReplaceableCollection
And it's built from a couple of
它是由一些其他的
other order n algorithms.
O(n) 算法构成的
The first is a half stable
第一个是 halfStablePartition
partition, which moves all of
它将所有
the elements satisfying some
满足某些谓词的元素
predicate to the end and tells
移动到末尾
us where that suffix starts.
并告诉我们后缀从哪里开始
The half stable in its name,
halfStable 正如其名
that comes, that indicates that
表明了
it preserves the order of the
它保留了不移动的
elements that it doesn't move,
元素的顺序
but it can scramble the elements
但是它也可以打乱
that it moves to the end.
移动到最后的元素
Now, sometimes, that doesn't
有些时候
matter though; the second
这不是很重要
algorithm removes subrange.
因为第二个算法 removeSubrange()
It's just going to delete them
无论如何也会
anyway.
删除子区间
Have we all seen this partial
我们都见过这个
range notation?
部分区间的标记吗
It's just a really convenient
它是一种非常方便的
way of writing a range that
方式来编写扩展到
extends to the end of the
集合末尾的范围
Okay.
好的
Now, remove subrange is part of
现在 removeSubrange 是
the library's public API, so you
库全局 API 的一部分
can find its documentation
因此你可以在网上找到它的文档
online, but halfStablePartition
但是 halfStablePartition
is an implementation detail.
是一个运行的细节
Now, we're not going to step
现在 我们不打算
through all of it, but there are
一一介绍 但是这里有一些
a few things worth noticing
值得注意的地方
First, it starts by calling yet
首先 它一开始
another algorithm,
调用另一个算法
firstIndex(where), to find the
firstIndex(where: )
position of the first element
来查找属于后缀的
that belongs in the suffix.
第一个元素的位置
Next, it sets up a loop variable
接下来 它设置了一个循环变量 j
j, and there's a single loop,
有一个循环
and the loop index j moves
然后这个循环指数 j 在每次迭代中
forward one on each iteration.
会从前向后移动一位
So, it's a sure bet that j makes
所以 可以肯定的是
just one pass over the elements.
j 只对元素进行了一次传递
You can almost see the order and
你几乎可以从这里看到
complexity just from that.
量级和复杂度
Lastly, because this method
最后 由于该方法
needs to rearrange elements but
需要重新排列元素
not change the length or
但不更改
structure of the collection, it
集合的长度或结构
only depends on mutable
因此它只依赖于对
collection conformance.
MutableCollection 的遵循
So, this is the first lesson I
所以 这就是我学到的第一堂课
Become familiar with what's in
熟悉 Swift
the Swift Standard Library.
标准库中的内容
It contains a suite of
它包含一组
algorithms with documented
提供文档描述
meanings and performance
和性能特征的算法
And although we happened to peek
虽然我们看了一点执行过程
at the implementation, and you
你也可以从中学到很多东西
can learn a lot that way, it's
但由于它是设计好的
designed so that you do not have
所以你不必用我之前的笨方法
The official documentation
官方文档会告诉你
should tell you everything you
需要知道的一切
need to know in order to use the
以便有效地使用该库
You'll even find a playground
你甚至可以在那找到
tutorial there.
一个 Playground 教程
Now, I realize there's a lot in
我知道 Swift 中有很多内容
Swift, so it can look daunting,
所以它的确可能看起来很吓人
but you don't need to remember
但是你不需要记住一切
Having an idea of what's there
知道那里有什么
and how to find it will take you
以及如何找到它将
a long way.
为你省下很多精力
Now, before we move on, I want
现在 在我们继续之前
to point out something else that
我想指出
happened in my code when Crusty
当 Crusty 做出此更改时
made this change.
在代码中发生的其他事情
Which one of these most directly
这两个中哪一个最直接地
describes its meaning?
描述了它的意义
Now, I actually have to read and
现在 我必须先通读
think through the first one to
并思考第一个
know what it's doing.
才能知道它在做什么
Hmm.
嗯
Maybe I'd better add a comment.
也许我最好加个注释
Okay.
好的
How does that look?
看起来怎么样
Oh, even with that comment, the
哦 即使有了评论
reverse iteration is kind of
反向迭代仍旧有点棘手
tricky, and I don't want
而且我也不想
somebody breaking this code
有人因为他们不理解而破坏
it.
这个代码
So, I'd better explain that.
所以我最好解释一下
Okay.
好的
While we're clarifying things,
当我们一一澄清时
the After code actually reads
Crusty 改过的代码实际上更好理解
better with a trailing closure
因为它有一个
syntax.
尾随闭包语法
Now, take a breath and look
现在 让我们深呼吸
again.
然后再看
Which one is more obviously
哪一个更明显是正确的
Even with all these comments, I
即使带有这些评论
still need to read through the
我仍然需要通读第一个
first one just to see that it
去明白它其实和第二个
does inefficiently the same
做的是同样的事
thing as the second one.
但是效率更低
Using the algorithm just made
使用这个算法可以使代码
the code better in every way.
在各个方面都做得更好
So, this is a guideline, an
所以 这是你的代码的
aspiration for your code first
一个准则 也是一个目标
put forward by Shawn Perin.
是由 Sean Parent 首先提出的
Every time you write a loop,
每当你编写一个循环时
replace it with a call to an
就用对某个算法的调用
algorithm.
来替换它
If you can't find one, make that
如果你找不到对应的算法
algorithm yourself and move the
就自己做一个算法
loop into its implementation.
然后用这个算法来执行循环
Actually following this might
实际上 现在对你来说
seem unrealistic to you now, but
这似乎是不现实的
by the end of the talk, I hope
但是在谈话的最后
it won't.
我希望它不再是这样
For a little motivation though,
不过为了获得一点动力
think back to the last time you
回想一下上一次
were looking at spaghetti code.
你看到乱得像面条一样的代码的时候
Was it full of loops?
是不是充满了循环
I bet it was.
我打赌一定是
All right.
好吧
Done and done.
大功告成
I have just made the code
我已经使代码
shorter, faster, and better in
变得更短 更快
every way.
在各个方面都更好
I was ready to call it a day.
我准备今天到此为止
"Thanks for your help, Crusty,"
“感谢你的帮助 Crusty”
I said, fastening the titanium
我说 同时系上
carabiners on my bespoke leather
我定制的皮革邮差包上的钛制钩环
messenger bag, but he looked at
但他怀疑地看着我
me suspiciously, and said, "You
然后说
suppose you might have made that
“你不认为你可能在别的地方
mistake anywhere else?"
犯过那样的错误吗”
I sighed, put my bag down and
我叹了口气 把包放下
started hunting down the loops
开始追踪我代码中的循环
There were lots in the file
然后我发现 在处理层级命令的
[inaudible].
文件中 有很多
Bring to front, send it back,
放到最前 放到最后
bring forward, which sort of
向前移动一层
hops the selected shape over the
也就是把选定的图形移到
one in front of it.
前面的图形上
Let's do that a couple of more
让我们来多做几次吧
times.
向后移动
the shape, below the selected
放在选定的图形下面
shape, and last of all, dragging
最后
in the shape list at the left.
在左边的图形列表中拖拽
Now, these sound really simple
现在 这些操作听起来非常简单
until you realize that they all
直到你意识到
need to operate on multiple
它们都需要对多个选定的图形进行操作
selected shapes that might not
这些图形在列表中
even be contiguous in the list.
甚至可能都不是连续的
So, it turns out that the
因此结果表明
behavior that makes sense is to
在操作完成后
leave all of the selected
将所有选定的元素
elements next to each other
放在一起
after the operation is finished.
才是有意义的
So, when you're bringing shapes
所以 当你把图形向前移动时
forward, you hop the front most
你把选定的最前面的图形
selected shape in front of its
放在紧邻它的图形前面
neighbor, and then you group all
然后你把所有其他的图形
the other ones behind it.
放在它后面
And when you send shapes
当你向后移动图形时
backward, you hop the bottom
你把选定的最后面的图形
most selected shape backward
放在紧邻它的图形后面
behind its neighbor and group
然后把其他的图形
the other ones in front of it.
放在它前面
So, if you didn't follow that
如果你没有完全跟上
completely, don't worry.
不要担心
We'll come back to it.
我们会回头再讲
But suffice it to say that I had
但我只想说
some pretty carefully worked out
我有一些精心设计的代码
code to get all of these details
来正确地处理所有这些细节 就足够了
For example, this was
例如 这是 bringToFront()
bringToFront, and when I looked
当我看到它时
at it, sure enough, there was an
我十分地确定
order n loop over the shapes
这些图形有一个 O(n) 的循环
containing two order n
还包含两个 O(n) 的运算
operations, remove(at:) and
remove(at:)  insert(at:)
insert(at:), which makes this,
这就产生了
you guessed it, n squared.
没错 n 的二次方
In fact, that same problem
事实上 同样的问题
showed up in every one of my
出现在每一个
other four commands.
我其他的四个命令中
All of the implementations here
这里的所有执行
loop over an array, performing
都对数组进行循环
insertions and removals, which
执行插入和删除操作
means they're all quadratic.
这意味着它们都是二次的
Now, I was kind of discouraged
现在 我有点气馁
at this point, so I asked Crusty
所以我问 Crusty
if he'd look at them with me.
他是否愿意和我一起看
He said, "Can't stay too late,"
他说 “我不能待太晚”
he said, "I got my ballroom
他说 “我今晚有一个
dancing tonight, but I guess we
交际舞聚会 但是我想
better get a move on."
我们还是抓紧继续吧”
So, I pulled up bringToFront,
我在 bringToFront() 这里停下来
and Crusty's first question was,
Crusty 的第一个问题是
"What does it actually do?"
“它到底是做什么的”
"Well," I said, "there's a while
“好吧” 我说 “这是个 while 循环
loop and j tracks the insertion
j 跟踪插入点
point and i tracks the element
i 跟踪我们正在
we're looking at."
查看的元素
"In words, not in codes," said
“用语言 而不是用代码”
Crusty.
Crusty 说“描述它”
"Okay. Let's see.
“好吧 我们来看看
It moves the selected shapes to
它将选定的图形移动到前面
the front, maintaining their
保持它们的相对顺序”
"Write that down in a dot
“把它写在点注释上
comment and read it back to me."
然后读给我听”
I'm a superfast typist.
我是一个手速超快的打字员
"Moves the selected shapes to
“将选定的图形移动到前面
the front, maintaining their
保持它们的相对顺序”
"Sound familiar?"
“听起来熟悉吗”
said Crusty.
Crusty 说
That's when I realized that this
就在那时我意识到
was a lot like half stable
它很像 halfStablePartition
partition, except it's fully
但它是完全稳定的
stable.
我开始激动起来
And what do you think this one
“你觉得这个叫什么”
So, I had to guess, "Stable
我不得不猜
partition?"
“stablePartition”
"That's right.
“没错
One of my old favorites, and you
我最喜欢的一个
can find an implementation in
你可以在这个 Swift 开源项目中
this here file from the Swift
找到一个
Open Source project."
执行文件”
So, I pulled the file into my
因此 我把文件拖进了我的项目中
project, while Crusty mumbled
同时 Crusty 含糊地说
something about how that comment
我们添加的注释
we added should have been there
应该在一开始就写上
all along, and I started coding,
我开始编写代码
getting about this far before I
写了这么多 就又遇到了一个问题
You see, stable partition takes
你看 stablePartition 使用了一个谓词
a predicate that says whether to
它表示是否将元素
move an element into the suffix
移动到集合的后缀中
So, I had to express bring to
所以 要把东西搬到后面
front in terms of moving things
我需要执行
to the back.
bringToFront()
I looked at Crusty.
我看向 Crusty
"Visualize it," he said.
“脑补一下” 他说
So, I closed my eyes and watched
于是 我闭上眼睛
as the unselected shapes
看着那些未被选中的图形
gathered at the back, which gave
聚集在后面
me my answer.
这就给了我答案
Now, I guess sendToBack was even
我猜 sendToBack 会更加简单
easier because we just need to
因为我们只需
invert the predicate.
反转谓词
We're sending the selected ones
我们将选定的图形
to the back.
移动到后面
Now, I was just about to attack
现在 我正准备执行
the bring forward command, and I
向前移动的命令
figured that Crusty would be as
我想 Crusty 会和我一样
eager to move on as I was, given
急于继续
his plans for the evening, but
考虑到他晚上的计划
he stopped me.
但他阻止了我
"Hold your horses, Snuffy.
“刹车 Snuffy
I don't want to miss the opening
我不想错过开场探戈
tango, but aren't you going to
但你不打算看看
check whether it'll scale?"
它能不能延展尺寸吗”
He had a point, so I popped up
他有道理 所以我弹出 stablePartition 的
the Quick Help for stable
“Quick Help”
partition, and I saw that it had
然后看到它的复杂度
(n log n) complexity.
是 O(n log n)
So, for a way to think about (n
为了有一个 O(n log n) 的概念
log n) take a look at log n.
我们不妨看看 O(log n)
It starts to level off really
它从开始很快就进入
quickly, and the bigger it gets,
平稳状态 n 越大
the slower it grows, and the
它增长的越慢
closer it comes to being a
越接近一个常数
So, when you multiply that by n,
所以当你乘 n 时
you get something that doesn't
你所得到延展性图像
scale quite as well as order n
与 O(n) 的并不同
but that gets closer and closer
但是随着它的增长它
to linear as it grows.
越来越接近线性
So, order n login is rightly
所以 O(n log n)
often treated as being almost
通常被认为
the same as order n.
和 O(n) 差不多
I was pretty happy with that.
我对此十分开心
So, we moved on to bring
所以我们继续处理
forward.
bringFoward()
Now, as we said earlier, bring
现在 就像我们之前说过的
forward bumps the front most
bringFoward() 将最前面选定的图形
selected shape forward by one
向前移动一层
position and gathers the other
并将后面的其他
selected shapes behind it.
被选定的图形聚集起来
But Crusty didn't like that way
但是 Crusty 根本不喜欢
of thinking about it at all.
这种思考方法
"That little do-si-do at the
“刚开始的时候
beginning is making a line dance
那个绕来绕去的东西 让那行代码
look like a Fox Trot."
像是在跳狐步舞狐步舞”
he said, "You don't need it."
他说 “你并不需要它”
When I looked at him blankly, he
当我茫然地看着他的时候
broke out the lozenges again,
他又拿出了薄荷糖
and with five of his free
用他五根灵活的手指
digits, he executed the
执行了
bringForward command.
bringForward() 指令
"See it again?"
“看到了吗”
he asked.
他问
I felt a little like a mark in a
我感觉就像 明知道“赌徒三张”是一个陷阱
Three-card Monte, but I played
但我还是踩了进去
along.
“看着熟悉吗”
"No."
“不”
He threw a hanky over the first
他用手帕盖住了前几个
"How about now?"
“现在呢”
That's when I realized it was
就在这时我意识到
just another stable partition.
这就是另一个 stablePartition
Okay.
好吧
I got this, I thought.
我明白了 我想
If we find the front most
如果我们找到选定的
selected shape, then move to its
最前面的图形
predecessor, and isolate the
然后移动到它前面图形的位置
section of the array that starts
并隔离从那里开始的数组的部分
there, we could just partition
我们可以对它进行分区
"But how do you modify just part
“但是，你如何只修改
of a collection?"
集合中的一部分呢”
I asked Crusty.
我问 Crusty
"Ain't you never heard of a
“你难道没听说过切片吗”
he said, taking over the
他说 同时接管了键盘
"Shapes, starting with
“shapes
predecessor.
[predecessor...]
There.
好了
Stick that in your algorithm and
把它放在你的算法里
mutate it."
然后进行变换”
Which I promptly did.
我立即照做
So, human knowledge about how to
因此 人类关于如何
compute things correctly and
正确有效地
efficiently predates computers
计算事物的知识
by thousands of years, going
要比计算机早几千年
back at least to ancient Egypt,
至少可以追溯到古埃及
and since the invention of
自从计算机发明以来
computers, there's been an
这一领域的工作
explosion of work in this area.
出现了爆炸式增长
If the standard library doesn't
如果标准库没有
have what you need, what you do
你所需要的
need is probably out there with
那么你需要做的
tests, with documentation, often
可能是测试 阅读文档
with a proof of correctness.
通常更正后还要检查一下
Learn how to search the web for
要学会如何在网络上
research that applies to your
搜索适用于
problem domain.
你的问题领域的研究
Okay.
好的
Back to the code.
回到代码上来
I was intrigued by this slice
我对这个切片很感兴趣
thing, and when I checked out
当我检查它的类型时
its type, I saw that it wasn't
我发现它不是一个数组
Since we had used stable
由于我们是在一个数组上
partition on an array and
使用了 stablePartition
bringToFront and sendToBack, and
bringToFront 以及 sendToBack
now we were using it on an array
现在我们还在一个数组切片上使用它
slice, I guessed out loud that
所以我大胆猜测
it must be generic.
它一定是通用的
"Of course, it is.
“当然是
What's stable partition got to
stablePartition
do with the specifics of array?"
和特定的数组有什么关系”
"That's right, nothing.
“没错 没有联系
Speaking of which, Blonkey, just
说到这 豆包
what does bringForward have to
bringForward() 与图形和选择
do with shapes and selection?"
又有什么关系呢”
"Well," I said, "it works on
“嗯” 我说 “它作用于图形
shapes, and it brings forward
然后将选定的图形
the selected ones."
移到前面”
"That's right, nothing," he went
“没错 也没关系”
on without listening.
他听都没听便说道
"Can you run bring forward on a
“你能在一排薄荷糖上
row of lozenges?
执行向前移动吗
Of course, you can.
当然 你可以
So, it's got nothing to do with
所以 这和图形
shapes."
没有关系”
Hmm.
嗯
"Are you suggesting we make it
“你是在建议我们让它
generic?"
变得通用吗”
I asked.
我问道
"Isn't that premature
“难道它不早就是
generalization?"
通用的了吗”
Answering a question with a
用一个新问题回答了这个问题
question, Crusty replied, "Well,
Crusty 回答道
just how do you plan to test
“唔 你打算怎样
this method?"
测试这个方法”
"Okay," I said, "I'll create a
“好的” 我说
canvas.
“我会创造一个画布
I'll add a bunch of random
我会添加一些随机的图形
shapes.
我会选定它们中的一些
then finally..."
然后最终”
But I didn't even finish the
但我的话没有说完
sentence because I knew it was a
因为我知道
bad idea.
这是个坏主意
If I did all of that, would I
如果我就这么做
really be testing my function,
我真的会测试我的功能吗
or would I be testing the
还是我会测试
initializers of Canvas and
画布和不同图形的初始化设定
various shapes, the addShape
addMethod() 方法
method, the isSelected property
再或者测试
of the various shapes if it's
各种形状的 isSelected 属性是否
computed?
计算出来
I have to build test cases for
我的确应该建立测试用例
sure, but ideally, that code
但是理想情况下
shouldn't depend on other code
那段代码不应取决于其他
that I also have to test.
我需要再测试的代码
If I can bring the lozenges
如果我可以将薄荷糖向前移
forward, it should be possible
那么我也应有可能
to do something casual with
用 Playground 中的整数
[inaudible] in a playground,
做一些随机的事
like this, which brings forward
就像这样 用 bringForward() 方法
the number divisible by 3.
把能被 3 整除的数提到前面来
Now, at the other end of the
现在 在频谱的另一端
spectrum, I should be able to
我应该可以向它抛出
throw vast quantities of
大量随机生成的测试数据
it and make sure that the
并确保算法的
algorithm scales.
可扩展性
Neither of those was going to be
只要代码与画布和图形
easy as long as the code was
绑定在一起
tied to Canvas and shapes.
这些事情就都不会简单
And so, I admitted to Crusty
所以 我向 Crusty 承认他是对的
making this non-generic
并开始把这个非通用的
bringForward into a generic one.
bringForward() 变成通用的算法
The first step was to decouple
第一步是将它
it from Canvas and move it to
从画布中解耦出来
arrays of shapes.
并将其移动到图形数组中
Of course, this array is the
当然 这个数组就是 shapes
shape, so I had to replace
所以我必须用 self
shapes with self, and then I
把它替换掉
decoupled it from selection by
然后我通过传递一个谓词
passing a predicate indicating
将它从选择中解耦出来
whether a given shape should be
该谓词指示是否应该将选定的图形
brought forward.
向前移动
And everything kept compiling.
一切都在正常编译着
Awesome!
太棒了
At that point, I was pleased to
此时 我很高兴地发现
find there were no dependencies
在 shapes 上没有依赖
left on shape, and I could just
我可以删除
delete the where clause.
where 子句了
Pretty cool, I thought.
非常好 我想
Now, I can bring forward on any
现在 我可以在任何数组中
array.
执行 bringForward 了
I looked over at Crusty, who had
我看了看 Crusty
been quietly practicing the
他一直在角落里
cha-cha-cha in the corner, but
安静地练习恰恰舞
he didn't seem to think I was
但他似乎认为我还
finished.
没有结束
"What does bring forward have to
“bringForward() 和数组
do with arrays?"
有什么关系”他问
"Well, nothing," I sighed and
“好吧 的确没有” 我叹了口气
started thinking about how to
然后开始思考
remove this dependency.
如何移除这个依赖
Let's see, there's a stable
让我们看看
partition here, which requires
这有一个 stablePartition()
mutable collection conformance.
需要遵循 MutableCollection
So, maybe I'll just move it to
所以 也许我只需要将它移动到
mutable collection.
MutableCollection 中
Hmm.
嗯
I thought, clearly the index
我想 显然索引类型
type doesn't match Int.
与 int 类型不匹配 好吧
Okay.
这应该很好修复 对吧
Have you done this?
你是这么做的吗
Don't do this.
不要这么做
It compiled, but Crusty had
它编译好了
suddenly stopped dancing, and I
但是 Crusty 突然停止了跳舞
knew something was wrong.
我知道有些不对劲
"What?" I said.
“什么” 我说
"Rookies always do that," said
“菜鸟总是这样做”
Crusty, shaking his head.
Crusty 边摇着头边说
"First, you got that comparison
“首先 你让它与 0 的比较
with 0, which is going to be
这对于数组切片来说是错误的
So, did you know that array
所以 你知道数组切片
slices, their indices don't
它们的索引不是
start at 0?
从 0 开始的吗
The indices of all slices start
所有切片的索引
with the corresponding index in
从它们被切片的
the underlying collection that
底层集合中的
they were sliced from.
相应索引开始
That relationship is critical if
这种关系十分关键
you want to be able to compose
如果你想要用切片
generic algorithms using slices,
组成通用算法
so it's really important."
所以它真的很重要”
Well, this problem, I knew to
好吧 我知道要修正这个问题
Just compare it with start
只需将它与开始索引
index.
进行比较
But the real problem is "What
但是真正的问题是
does bringForward have to do
“bringForward() 与拥有整数索引
with having integer indices?"
有什么关系”
I interrupted.
我打断了他
"Yeah, I know."
“是的 我知道”
"Well, I do have to get the
“我必须在 i 之前
index before i, which I can do
得到索引
with subtraction."
我可以用减法获得”
Crusty just sighed and broke out
Crusty 只是叹了口气
the lozenges again.
然后又将薄荷糖拿了出来
And then, he laid two fingers
然后 他把两个手指
down on the desk and walked them
放在桌子上 像小人一样走啊走
across until his right hand was
直到右手指向
pointing at the first green
第一块绿色的薄荷糖
"Not a backwards step in the
“整支舞中都没有
whole dance," he said.
向后的舞步” 他说
And I realized that Crusty had
之后我意识到
just shown me a new algorithm.
Crusty 刚刚向我展示了一个新的算法
Let's call that one
“我们叫它
indexBeforeFirst.
indexBeforeFirst 吧”
"Now, the trick here is to keep
“现在 这里的诀窍是
your focus by assuming somebody
保持注意力集中
already wrote it for you."
假设有人已经为你写了它”
And he proceeded to hack away
然后他把我们不需要的
all the code that we didn't
代码都删掉了
need, like that and that.
像这样 这样
"Predecessor is the index before
“predecessor 就是第一个
the first one where the
在谓词被满足之前的元素
predicate is satisfied.
前面的索引
Now, just look how pretty that
现在 快来看看这读起来
reads."
多么动人”
Now, if you look at it, you can
如果你看到了这个代码
see that he's right.
你就会发现他是对的
Taking away all the irrelevant
删除所有无关的细节
detail about shapes, selections,
包括图形 选择
arrays, and integers had left me
数据以及整数
with clearer code because it
给我留下更清晰的代码
only traffics in the essentials
因为它只处理
of the problem.
问题的本质
"I already showed you how
“我已经向你展示了
indexBeforeFirst works.
indexBeforeFirst 是如何工作的
See if you could write it," he
试一试你能不能写出来” 他说
So, I think I was starting to
所以 我想我现在开始
catch on now because I got it
跟得上他了
right the first time.
因为我第一次做对了
I told you, I'm a superfast
我说过 我是个手速超快的打字员
All right.
好吧
So, return the first index whose
所以 返回第一个
successor matches the predicate.
successor 与谓词匹配的索引
I was pretty excited about how
我非常兴奋地看到
well this was going.
这进展得有多么顺利
"All right, Crusty," I said,
“好吧 Crusty” 我说
"let's do the next one."
“让我们做下一个”
"Ain't you forgetting something,
“你难道没有忘记什么事吗
Bonkey?"
豆包” 他问道
he asked.
我不知道
talking about.
他在说什么
The code was clean, and it
代码很简洁
worked.
而且运行正常
"Semantics, son.
“语义 小子
How am I supposed to use these
我怎么能从其他代码中使用它们
from other code if I don't know
如果我不知道
what they mean?"
它们是什么意思呢”
And that's when I realized every
于是我意识到
time we'd use the new algorithm,
每一次我们使用新的算法
we had leaned on his
我们都依靠他的文档
documentation to draw
得出关于
conclusions about the meaning
我们自己代码的
and efficiency of our own code.
意义和效率的结论
And because most algorithms are
因为大多数算法都是
built out of other algorithms,
由其他算法构建的
they lean on the same thing.
所以它们依赖于相同的东西
Recently, I was interviewing a
最近 我正在面试一位
perspective intern and asked him
未来的实习生并且问他
about the role of documentation,
关于文档的作用
and he began with a phrase I
他以一个我不会忘记的
won't forget.
短语开始
"Oh, it's incredibly important,"
“哦 它实在太重要了” 他说
"We're building these towers of
“我们正在构建这些抽象的塔”
abstraction," and now I'm
我在向你们复述他的话
paraphrasing, "the reason we can
“我们之所以能够成功构建
build without constantly
而无需经常检查
inspecting the layers below us
下面层级的内容
is that the parts that we build
是因为我们构建的部分
on are documented."
是有文档记录的”
Now, as an app developer, you
现在 作为一名 App 开发者
are working at the very top of a
你正在一个塔尖上工作
tower that stretches through
这个塔贯穿了
your system frameworks, DOS, and
你的系统框架 DOS
into the hardware, which rests
一直延伸到硬件
on the laws of physics.
这是基于物理定律的
But as soon as you call one of
但是一旦你调用了
your own methods, it becomes
你自己的方法
part of your foundation; so,
它就成为你的基础的一部分
document your code.
所以 请为你的代码写文档
The intern was hired, by the
顺便说一下
way, and he's sitting right
那位实习生被录用了
there.
他就坐在那里
So, I took the hint and
所以 我接受了提示
documented Crusty's new
并把 Crusty 的新算法写入了文档
algorithm, which meant that we
这意味着
could forget about the
我们可以忘记
implementation and just use it,
它如何实现 并使用它
knowing that Quick Help had
因为我们知道 “Quick Help”
everything that we needed.
拥有我们所需要的一切
Now, I also documented
现在 我也记录了 bringForward
Cool!
酷
Now, because it seemed to be
现在 因为它似乎
solving all of my problems, at
解决了我所有的问题
this point, I was really curious
在这时 我真的很好奇
to see what was going on inside
想看看在 stablePartition 里
stablePartition.
发生了什么
It turns out I was well rewarded
结果是我得到了很好的回报
because it's a really beautiful
因为这是一个非常漂亮
and instructive algorithm.
而且有指导意义的算法
The public method gets the
这个公共的方法
collections count and passes it
获取集合计数
on to this helper, which uses a
并将其传递给这个 helper 方法
divide and conquer strategy.
该 helper 方法使用“分而治之”的策略
So, first, it takes care of the
首先 它会处理基本情况
base cases when the count is
当计数小于 2 时
less than 2, we're done.
我们便结束了
We just need to figure out
我们只需要弄清楚
whether the partition point is
分区点是在
at the beginning or at the end
集合的开始处
of the collection.
或者在集合的末尾
Next, we divide the collection
接下来 我们将集合
in two.
分成两部分
Now, at this point, you have to
现在 在这一点上
temporarily take it on faith
你必须暂时相信
that the algorithm works because
算法是有效的
we're going to stable partition
因为我们要用 stablePartition() 处理
the left half and the right
左半边和右半边
Now, if you take a look at these
现在 如果你看一下这两端
two ends, you can see that
你会发现
everything is exactly in the
所有东西都在正确的位置
right place, but this center
但是这个中心区段
section has two parts that need
有两个部分
to be exchanged.
需要交换
Now, they won't always have the
现在 它们不会总是
same length as they do in this
和在这个例子中一样长
example, and fortunately there's
幸运的是
an algorithm for that.
“有一个算法可以使用”
We call it rotate.
我们叫它 rotate()
Okay.
好的
I'm not going to go into rotate
我不打算在这里深入讨论 rotate 算法
here, but it's actually quite
但是它真的很漂亮
beautiful, and if you're
如果你感兴趣
interested, you can find its
你可以在与 stablePartition 同样的文件中
as stable partitions.
找到它的实现方法
Okay.
好的
Back to shapes.
回到图形
Now, this mess implemented the
现在 这个烂摊子实现了
dragging in the shapes list, and
在图形列表中拖放
it had always been one of my
这一直是我最复杂
most complicated and buggy
和 Bug 最多的运算之一
The strategy had been to
我的策略是
allocate the temporary buffer;
分配临时缓冲区
then, loop over the shapes
然后在插入点之前
before the insertion point,
对 shapes 进行循环
extracting the selected ones and
提取选定的图形
adjusting the insertion point,
并调整插入点
and then separately loop over
然后在不调整插入点的情况下
the rest of the shapes without
分别对其余的图形
adjusting the insertion point,
进行循环
extracting the selected ones.
提取选定的图形
And then, finally, reinsert
最后 重新插入它们
Honestly, I was a little scared
老实说 我有点害怕触碰代码
thought I finally had it right.
因为我觉得我终于做对了
It had been almost a week since
距离我最后一次发现新 Bug
the last time I discovered a new
已经差不多有
bug.
一个星期了
But I had gotten pretty good at
但是我现在已经在这个过程中
this process now, so I tried
做得很好了
visualizing the operation
所以我试着把操作可视化一次完成
Hey, that looks familiar.
嘿 看起来很熟悉
Let's see it again.
让我们再看看
Hmm.
嗯
Suppose we do this first, and
假设我们先做这个
then take care of the parts
然后分别处理
separately.
各个部分
That's right.
没错
This is just two stable
这就是两个
partitions with inverted
带有反转谓词的 stablePartition
So, the generic algorithm
所以 这个通用的算法
collapsed down to this
被压缩到了这两行
two-liner, and here's what's
而这是 Canvas 上剩下的
Now, let's just see that next to
现在 让我们把它放在
the old code.
旧代码旁边看看
That's not bad, but we got a
还不错 但是我们得到了
reusable efficient documented
一个可重复使用的
general purpose algorithm out of
高效文档化的通用算法
it, which is spectacular.
这是非常棒的
Okay.
好的 这是一种需要习得的技能
look past the details that are
审视特定于你的 App
specific to your application
领域的细节
domain, see what your code is
了解你的代码从根本上在做什么
doing fundamentally, and capture
并在可重复使用的通用代码中
that in reusable generic code.
捕获这些细节
It takes practice.
这需要实践
So, why bother?
但是 为什么要那么麻烦呢
Well, the practical answer is
实践得到的答案是
that because they're decoupled
因为它们是从无关的细节中
from those irrelevant details,
解耦出来的
generic algorithms are more
通用的算法更加
reusable, testable, and even
可重复使用 经得起考验
clearer than their non-generic
甚至比对应的非通用代码
counterparts.
更加简洁
But I also think it's just
但我也认为
deeply rewarding for anyone that
对于任何真正喜欢编程的人来说
really loves programming.
这都是非常有益的
It's a search for truth and
它是对真与美的追求
beauty but not some abstract
而不是抽象的
untouchable truth because the
不可触及的真理
constraints of actual hardware
因为实际硬件的约束
keep you honest.
让你保持诚实
As Crusty likes to say,
就像 Crusty 常说的
"Programming reveals the real."
“编程揭示本真”
So, treat your computation as a
因此 将你的计算视为
first class citizen with all the
具有类型
rights and obligations that you
和 App 体系结构的
take seriously for types and
具有权利和义务的 VIP
Identify it, give it a name,
标识它 给它一个名字
unit test it, and document its
对它进行单元测试
semantics and performance.
并记录它的语义和性能
Now, I want to close by putting
最后 我想把
this advice you saw from Shawn
Sean Parent 的建议
Perin in its full context.
包括上下文引用一下 作为结束语
"If you want to improve the code
“如果你想要提高
quality in your organization,
组织中的代码质量
replace all of your coding
请将所有的代码标准
standards with one goal, No Raw
替换为一个目标 不要单独写循环”
Thank you.
谢谢大家
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]